[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398dc", "question": "What was the name of the Cartwright's ranch on the TV show \"Bonanza\"?", "answer": "Ponderosa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5db03f91aa1c9af2684d79a7", "question": "Which college did Bill Gates drop out from?", "answer": "Harvard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa56f73838c5c8a417f25", "question": "Which insect has the shortest lifespan?", "answer": "Mayfly", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff3cffa4f032c0db195b495", "question": "What was the name of the military nobility of medieval and early-modern Japan?", "answer": "Samurai", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e49", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"The Dirty Dozen\"?", "answer": "Jim Brown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b715", "question": "The album, Sacred Arias was released by what blind Italian tenor?", "answer": "Andrea Bocelli", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af987cbaeb0982ee4559554", "question": "What Beatles song is referenced in the opening verse to Bad Company's \"Shooting Star\"?", "answer": "Love Me Do", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb59b55dad637d903c8814", "question": "What is the modern name for Van Diemen\u2019s Land?", "answer": "Tasmania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "590087145304ceedb84e8993", "question": "In which US state is George A. Romero's 1968 film \"Night of the Living Dead\" set?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c061", "question": "What is the nickname of the patient in the game \"Operation\"?", "answer": "Cavity Sam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3da", "question": "What year did poet Sylvia Plath die?", "answer": "1963", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e2", "question": "What birthday does Bridget celebrate in the course of the book \"Bridget Jones's Diary\"?", "answer": "33rd", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339da7", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Seven Days in May\"?", "answer": "Fredric March", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ca3c8344f0f6af5b066632", "question": "What is the fear of frogs called?", "answer": "Ranidaphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a784", "question": "How many US state capital city\u2019s names begin with the letter \"S\"?", "answer": "6", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e08", "question": "What Shakespeare play begins with a meeting of the Weird Sisters?", "answer": "Macbeth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c86b877e98cb977789e4", "question": "Where can you see the petroglyphs of Newspaper Rock?", "answer": "Petrified Forrest National Park", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59cdb12065ff7d326b622a66", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Curium?", "answer": "Cm", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb21", "question": "In 1990, what did the World Health Organization officially remove from its list of \"mental illnesses\"?", "answer": "Homosexuality", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ff", "question": "Which character does Kevin Spacey play in the 1995 movie \"The Usual Suspects\"?", "answer": "Roger Kint/Keyser Soze", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b84d", "question": "What is the Hebrew word for peace, used as both a greeting and a farewell?", "answer": "Shalom", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69f3320565ad31a57c78b", "question": "Who was the first woman to run for President of the United States,?", "answer": "Victoria Woodhull", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc6", "question": "What was the name of the ship that Jason & his Argonauts sail in?", "answer": "Argo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339888", "question": "What colour was Oscar the Grouch during the first season of Sesame Street?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6d1", "question": "What is the capital of New Mexico?", "answer": "Santa Fe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c746", "question": "What is the largest living bird on Earth?", "answer": "The ostrich", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b21b", "question": "What city was Archduke Ferdinand killed in?", "answer": "Sarajevo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ef", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows\" what does the acronym RAB stand for?", "answer": "Regulus A. Black", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be28", "question": "What world's currency is the Linden dollar?", "answer": "Second Life", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2da", "question": "Who was Arthur Jefferson better known as?", "answer": "Stan Laurel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a6ee20565ad31a57c7e2", "question": "Who was the British commander at the Battle of Yorktown?", "answer": "General Charles Cornwallis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7dc", "question": "Which non-coastal western US state has the seagull as its official state bird?", "answer": "Utah", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b46b", "question": "Which duo was the first to reach the summit of Mount Everest in 1953?", "answer": "Sir Edmund Hillary and Tenzing Norgay", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cba", "question": "What is the third letter of the Greek alphabet?", "answer": "Gamma", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be89", "question": "What type of a tree killed Jackson Pollock?", "answer": "Oak", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1dd", "question": "What film won the 1944 Oscar for Best Picture?", "answer": "Casablanca", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4b4f49076251badbeac2", "question": "The month of July was named after whom?", "answer": "Julius Caesar-- It was named by the Roman Senate in honor of the Roman general and statesman, it being the\u00a0month\u00a0of his birth.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "591c3813815febcc896f9279", "question": "What is the eigth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Scorpio", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b019", "question": "Prior to Ronald Reagan, who was the last US president whose first and last name began with the same letter?", "answer": "Herbert Hoover", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067a2dff9c0647b50a8055", "question": "Which Japanese company manufactured the final videocassette recorder on July 22, 2016?", "answer": "Funai", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8c9", "question": "The eggs of what sturgeon are the preferred form of caviar?", "answer": "Beluga", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339250", "question": "What Stanley Kubrick movie was hyped: \"In Vietnam the wind doesn't blow, it sucks\"?", "answer": "Full Metal Jacket", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c3721815febcc896f926d", "question": "What is a group of mallards in flight called?", "answer": "A Sord", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c82", "question": "What year did Sting release his first solo album after leaving The Police?", "answer": "1985", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067dc4ff9c0647b50a8074", "question": "Which gaming franchise celebrated its 20th anniversary on February 27, 2016?", "answer": "Pokemon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c937", "question": "Which is a small flightless bird, also New Zealand's national symbol?", "answer": "Kiwi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59f9b7b6364247bf200fb875", "question": "What year did Belinda Carlisle release the song \"I Get Weak\"?", "answer": "1988", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f169fbf7c52aae91cc07d6", "question": "What US state is the Sturgis Pretzel House located in?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b661", "question": "In baseball, a \"gopher pitch\" is referred to as what?", "answer": "A pitch hit for a home run", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfdc", "question": "What sport did Andre Agassi's dad compete in?", "answer": "Boxing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339de2", "question": "What \"Desperate Housewives\" creator broke into TV as a personal assistant to actress Dixie Carter?", "answer": "Marc Cherry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133addc", "question": "Joan of Arc won several victories for France in which European war?", "answer": "Hundred Year's War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afd5", "question": "The image of Uncle Sam was first used during what war?", "answer": "War of 1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ebe", "question": "Whose series of thirteen children's books of thirteen chapters each ended in 2006 with \"The End\"?", "answer": "Lemony Snicket's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b571b2e67df192a942e3365", "question": "What year did Cracker Jack introduce their mascots - Sailor Jack and his dog, Bingo?", "answer": "1916", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a264", "question": "On what TV show did Alanis Morrisette appear in the 1980's?", "answer": "You Can't Do that On Television", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c9", "question": "Who was the last European head of state to be executed after being removed from power?", "answer": "Nicolae Ceausescu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a090", "question": "What was John Wayne's real name?", "answer": "Marion Morrison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339609", "question": "What was Tom Cruise's call sign in the 1986 movie \"Top Gun\"?", "answer": "Maverick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398fd", "question": "On July 10, 1975, Cher filed for divorce from what musician?", "answer": "Gregg Allman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b12", "question": "Which Lord of the Rings character has an alter ego called \"Gollum\"?", "answer": "Smeagol", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a975", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The States-General?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c704fbde8045e48466bc", "question": "What does \"Homo sapiens\" mean?", "answer": "Wise man -- Biological classifier Carolus Linnaeus declared us \"Homo sapiens\", which translates from Latin to \"wise man\".", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0da", "question": "In 1995, who became the first Republican Speaker of the House in 40 years?", "answer": "Newt Gingrich", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd6670ba5bfecdd737e086a", "question": "What US state was the first to ban drivers from talking on handheld devices?", "answer": "New York", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339631", "question": "What city was the setting for the 1994 movie \"Miracle on 34th Street\"?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ee7", "question": "How many bottles unexpectedly appear in the last verse of Police song \"Message in a Bottle\"?", "answer": "A hundred billion", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b76a", "question": "How many colors were there in the first boxes of Crayola crayons sold in 1903?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c332", "question": "What was the purpose of the ancient medicinal confection made from the marshmallow plant?", "answer": "To treat irritated mucous membranes and increase the flow of breast milk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339330", "question": "What actor played the role of Captain John McIntyre on the TV show \"M*A*S*H\"?", "answer": "Wayne Rogers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd69fe86c0f9723ab15cb30", "question": "How many U.S. states are called commonwealths?", "answer": "4", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015dfbcfe83fe1f2a824b7e", "question": "When did the Chinese Civil War begin?", "answer": "1927", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada3", "question": "Who was better known as Butch Cassidy?", "answer": "Robert Leroy Parker", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9e2", "question": "Sleeping sickness is carried by which insect?", "answer": "Tsetse fly", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa19", "question": "What is the name of the island that separates the two waterfalls at Niagara Falls?", "answer": "Goat Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec6", "question": "In what band did Roger, Andy, and John Taylor all play?", "answer": "Duran Duran", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd667a0a5bfecdd737e086b", "question": "What condition is singultus better known as?", "answer": "Hiccups", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133909c", "question": "Demeter is the goddess of what?", "answer": "Harvest and agriculture", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4a8", "question": "Which country were the 1948 Winter Olympic Games?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b827", "question": "What US state borders only one other?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd7d", "question": "Who was the first person to plant a vineyard in the Bible?", "answer": "Noah", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd48", "question": "In soccer, how many yellow cards lead to a player's disqualification?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe768aaeec85e375820b2a4", "question": "What country once had a banknote that featured a woman riding a shark?", "answer": "Cook Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a1", "question": "What does the abbreviation NATO stand for?", "answer": "North Atlantic Treaty Organization", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe766bceec85e375820b288", "question": "In what Tahitian bay did Captain Cook first land?", "answer": "Matavai Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f16a8af7c52aae91cc07de", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Tempest\", what are the names of the three spirits?", "answer": "Iris, Ceres and Juno", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8bb", "question": "In which decade was the first Vespa scooter manufactured in Italy?", "answer": "1940s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9f5", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Iceland?", "answer": "Gyrfalcon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a70f", "question": "Which is the largest Great Lake?", "answer": "Lake Superior", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5cefc089948005ec986edcdc", "question": "Who is the third member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Haseul", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbe276ce05a3942286ee9", "question": "The film \"The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo\" is set in what country?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cb6f877e98cb97778a1a", "question": "In which country are you likely to hear the cheer or toast \"Opa!\" during a celebration?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abc0", "question": "Tirana is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Albania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "595642f2803c1f1ebcc4a02e", "question": "Who took home the Academy of Country Music\u2019s Male Vocalist trophy every year between 2006 and 2010?", "answer": "Brad Paisley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133990a", "question": "What band, formed in 1977, was fronted by singer/guitarist Mark Knopfler?", "answer": "Dire Straits", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be0f", "question": "Why was Mary Mallon famous in the early 1900s for her signature dessert of peaches and ice cream?", "answer": "It gave people typhus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c379", "question": "What name is given to male rhinoceroses?", "answer": "Bulls", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5bd", "question": "Who explored the Hudson River in 1609?", "answer": "Henry Hudson", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60121c6763c99d48cd169b17", "question": "Who was the designer of the Statue of Liberty?", "answer": "French sculptor Fr\u00e9d\u00e9ric Auguste Bartholdi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb70", "question": "Who led the NFL in rushing yards four out of five years from 1972 to 1976?", "answer": "O.J. Simpson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa4436ce05a3942286eb0", "question": "What action hero was a champion cha cha dancer?", "answer": "Bruce Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ee0b08d98002fdd633d0", "question": "What is the fear of beards called?", "answer": "Pogonophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b7ffa573a3a814d89068c5a", "question": "Which film star's biography is called \"Neither Shaken Nor Stirred\"?", "answer": "Sean Connery's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a899b9360d398dc9cf7a69e", "question": "What is the atomic number of tungsten?", "answer": "74", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b243", "question": "What king was executed for the excesses of his inquisitional \"Star Chamber\"?", "answer": "Charles I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a54c", "question": "What river flows into the Pacific Ocean between Oregon and Washington?", "answer": "Columbia River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c8d", "question": "What violinist-bandleader was the first inductee into the Canadian Music Hall of Fame?", "answer": "Guy Lombardo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e0", "question": "What type of creature is a copperhead?", "answer": "A snake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133969a", "question": "The 1975 movie \"The Man Who Would Be King\" is based on the tales of which author?", "answer": "Rudyard Kipling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339443", "question": "Which Bond actor won an Academy Award for his role in \"The Untouchables\"?", "answer": "Sean Connery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eb0ccf83302ff91e464a0", "question": "What year was the luxury brand \"Tiffany & Co.\" founded?", "answer": "1837", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339940", "question": "In the Foreigner song \"Hot Blooded\", the singer has a fever of what temperature?", "answer": "103", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde8", "question": "Who invented the method he called \"rope-a-dope\"?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a3", "question": "What agricultural crop is Cuba's main export?", "answer": "Sugar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338afa", "question": "Which character killed Cock Robin?", "answer": "The Sparrow", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c09", "question": "The book \"Unsafe at Any Speed\", criticized what company?", "answer": "General Motors", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b58b", "question": "What meat is a Wiener Schnitzel traditionally made from?", "answer": "Veal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339933", "question": "What Martin Scorsese film was based on a 1986 book by Nicholas Pileggi about the Lucchese crime family?", "answer": "Goodfellas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feb34337e83c707845b20c8", "question": "Russia is the world\u2019s largest country (by area), and its largest city (by population) is its capital. What\u2019s the next \u00adlargest country for which this is the case?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a94e", "question": "The Great Barrier Reef sits off the coast of what Australian state?", "answer": "Queensland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede2266ce05a3942286dcd", "question": "\"Santa Baby\" contributed to which singer\u2019s fame?", "answer": "Eartha Kitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9daf9e748bb36357acdd6", "question": "What is the name of the bony covering over the gills of ray-finned fishes?", "answer": "Operculum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "590678ebff9c0647b50a804e", "question": "What month, in 2016, did the World Trade Organization announce an outbreak of the Zika virus?", "answer": "January", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c63a", "question": "Which bird lays the largest eggs?", "answer": "Ostrich", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afcc", "question": "What fort was built on Garden Key in the Dry Tortugas islands?", "answer": "Fort Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a47b", "question": "Which stretch of water is Europe's most northern boundary?", "answer": "Arctic Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdab55f0b8cce1e6fda704c", "question": "Caff\u00e8 corretto is espresso \"corrected\" with what substance?", "answer": "Alcohol", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ead", "question": "What screen legend made his final appearance in the movie \"The Score\"?", "answer": "Marlon Brando", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b998", "question": "In the standard Monopoly game, what place will you land on if you roll 9 when on Park Avenue?", "answer": "Oriental Avenue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aac1", "question": "Into what ocean does the Zambezi River flow?", "answer": "Indian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c0b", "question": "TV show character, Borat, hails from what country?", "answer": "Kazakhstan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397c2", "question": "Who said of his TV fame: \"To this day, people will call me Dan Arnold.\"?", "answer": "John Goodman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b501", "question": "What is another term for a badminton bird?", "answer": "Shuttlecock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a38b", "question": "What is the longest river in the world?", "answer": " The Nile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339206", "question": "What is Prince's surname?", "answer": "Nelson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cac7", "question": "What is the atomic number of tin?", "answer": "50", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4e7", "question": "What river divides Paris into the Right Bank and the Left Bank?", "answer": "The Seine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a3f", "question": "Which famous poem includes the line \"I am the master of my fate, I am the captain of my soul\"?", "answer": "Invictus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ffe", "question": "What British TV series featured Basil and Sybil?", "answer": "Fawlty Towers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c339", "question": "What is the acronym for Thomas A. Swift's Electric Rifle?", "answer": "Taser", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bb6", "question": "What character did actor George Lindsey play on \"The Andy Griffith Show\"?", "answer": "Goober Pyle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d2", "question": "In the TV show \"Knight Rider\", what does K.I.T.T.'s name stand for?", "answer": "Knight Industries Two Thousand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008cf8cf842fa4c4ba96a5", "question": "What is the capital of Poland?", "answer": "Warsaw", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca9", "question": "In what century did Leonardo Da Vinci paint the \"Mona Lisa\"?", "answer": "16th Century", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c26", "question": "Michael Jackson was called the King of what?", "answer": "Pop", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e94", "question": "What Harry Potter snacks come in flavors including earwax, booger, and vomit?", "answer": "Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ade4", "question": "In 1908 New York City passed the Sullivan Ordinance, which banned what?", "answer": "Women from smoking in public", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b719", "question": "What carol contains the words \"Fa-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la\"", "answer": "Deck the Halls", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3cff44f0f6af5b066636", "question": "\"Domingo\" is Spanish for what?", "answer": "Sunday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f9f4c58af848b908361b87f", "question": "What company did the founders of YouTube work for before starting YouTube?", "answer": "PayPal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad40", "question": "What was the name of the plane that dropped the atomic bomb on Nagasaki?", "answer": "Bockscar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b65f", "question": "What fast food chain offered a sandwich known as the \"Big Montana\"?", "answer": "Arby's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6f0", "question": "What unit of land measurement equals 43,560 square feet?", "answer": "An acre", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ef", "question": "In the TV show \"Growing Pains\", what was Boner's dad's name?", "answer": "Sylvester Stabone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe64117ae7e414034b5aea9", "question": "What was the worst maritime disaster in the U.S.?", "answer": "The steamboat \"Sultana\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab12", "question": "What is the capital of the Australian state of Tasmania?", "answer": "Hobart", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ad9e139e748bb36357acdf4", "question": "What is the reality TV show based on the Robertson Family?", "answer": "Duck Dynasty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339601", "question": "Where does Julia Roberts go shopping in the 1990 movie \"Pretty Woman\"?", "answer": "Rodeo Drive", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133943e", "question": "What does Morpheus tell Neo to follow in \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "The White Rabbit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baee", "question": "NAFTA is a trade agreement between the US and what other two countries?", "answer": "Mexico and Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b711", "question": "What contribution to Christmas is John Calcott Horsely credited with?", "answer": "The first mass-produced Christmas card", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe0db23fcbed638185eaa07", "question": "Which U.S. city has the most coffee shops per capita?", "answer": "Juneau, Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d470b0f8e329de4f877894", "question": "Who was the NBA's most valuable player in 1976, 1977 and 1980?", "answer": "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b159", "question": "How did Princess Diana die in 1997?", "answer": "Car accident", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597ddf7677980686f722d187", "question": "What city was host to the first official Association football game in 1863?", "answer": "London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a049", "question": "Who was the first man to appear on the cover of Playboy Magazine?", "answer": "Peter Sellers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a3b", "question": "What was the occupation of James Woods' character on the TV show \"Shark\"?", "answer": "Lawyer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5904a519cf93664eb10486c8", "question": "Following his split with Francine, who does Freddie Femur marry, in the \"Strangers in Paradise\" comic series?", "answer": "Casey Bullocks", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60078481bd51d85e222ab65b", "question": "Who said, \"A dog has the soul of a philosopher\"?", "answer": "Plato (The Greek philosopher believed the soul consisted of three parts - reason, spirit and appetite.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5971e08489261e916c8e09ac", "question": "What US state was \"Steak 'n Shake\" founded in?", "answer": "Illinois", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909caddbb53d1af658864d3", "question": "What ABC Original Movie, starring Jenny McCarthy, air on December 10, 2006?", "answer": "Santa Baby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a745", "question": "Which is the fourth largest US state in surface area?", "answer": "Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c8", "question": "Which eye color is normally dominant in humans?", "answer": "Brown", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf6", "question": "What drink is sometimes called \"the green fairy\"?", "answer": "Absinthe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f06801dd7bf43be5e7fa", "question": "What did office supply giant 3M originally do?", "answer": "Mining", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c85c", "question": "The scientist Bernard Vonnegut, brother of famed author Kurt Vonnegut, discovered what commercial use for silver iodide?", "answer": "Rainmaking", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ab99d3b21a8909e5c332d3f", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Magician's Nephew\"?", "answer": "C. S. Lewis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad9e232e748bb36357acdf9", "question": "What year did Alfred Hitchcock release his first American made film?", "answer": "1940", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339da5", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Being There\"?", "answer": "Jack Warden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fb1beeff497e33de8057919", "question": "How many points did LeBron James score in his very first NBA game?", "answer": "25", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b199", "question": "What Germany city hosted the 1972 Olympic games?", "answer": "Munich", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca08", "question": "What is a \"Blenheim Orange\"?", "answer": "Apple", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b80c", "question": "What sport has a hooker in a scrum?", "answer": "Rugby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba191874c93a3298b2128", "question": "Of which US state was Jimmy Carter Governor before he became president?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb86", "question": "What South African golfer is nicknamed \"The Big Easy\"?", "answer": "Ernie Els", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fea", "question": "In Greek mythology Penthesilea was the queen of which people?", "answer": "Amazons", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7be6a877e98cb9777895f", "question": "What continent contains the most fresh water?", "answer": "Antarctica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb64f25dad637d903c8832", "question": "Where is the world's longest golf course?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c3d", "question": "What year did actor Anthony Hopkins become a naturalized citizen of the US?", "answer": "2000", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339db5", "question": "In 2007, which comedian jumped from the roof of Cannes' Carlton Hotel wearing a giant bee costume?", "answer": "Jerry Seinfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ed8", "question": "What pieces of fruit contain three princesses in Sergei Prokofiev's most famous opera?", "answer": "Oranges", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9f0ecff048f679a45aaab", "question": "Verminophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Germs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a86f", "question": "What language is spoken in the Pacific capital city of Yaren?", "answer": "Nauruan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff25c3231a458464a93c47d", "question": "What kind of food is Avgolemono?", "answer": "A mixture of egg yolk, lemon juice and broth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b5a0e662d71a53650ffd", "question": "How did Jay Gatsby make his money in \"The Great Gatsby\"?", "answer": "Bootlegging", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a822", "question": "When facing Mount Rushmore, which president's head is farthest to your left?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff145cab0ee8c595b6d39bb", "question": "Richard Bachman is a pen name used by which American author?", "answer": "Steven King", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4bb", "question": "What year did the Comoros gain its independence from France?", "answer": "1975", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e3f", "question": "In what key is Johann Pachelbel's famous \"Canon\"?", "answer": "D", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd66309a5bfecdd737e084b", "question": "What was John Wayne\u2019s last movie?", "answer": "\"The Shootist\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cbbabb53d1af658864db", "question": "Which artist recorded the Christmas song \"Run Rudolph Run\" in 1958?", "answer": "Chuck Berry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e259fe83fe1f2a824b9e", "question": "Via what route did Russians manage to send some supplies to Leningrad during the German siege of the city?", "answer": "A supply route across Lake Ladoga", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adbc", "question": "Which country was split into zones by the 'Yalta Agreement'?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bccf", "question": "What fruit is most commonly added to yogurt to make Indian \"raita\"?", "answer": "Cucumber", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cdd98e347d002c297e4f2", "question": "Who wrote the collection of short stories on which Fiddler on the Roof was based?", "answer": "Sholem Aleichem", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca11", "question": "What is the fear of lice called?", "answer": "Pediculophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "594d05dc1a1c922dd1ac64a5", "question": "What two countries have square flags?", "answer": "Switzerland and Vatican City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d7d", "question": "Who was the real-life model for the character of Jack Stanton in the novel \"Primary Colors\"?", "answer": "Bill Clinton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bd05bbb40191c55fd523fb3", "question": "What is the most known horror video game involving ink?", "answer": "Bendy and the Ink Machine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ec0", "question": "\"The Da Vinci Code\" repeats the myth that the glass pyramid in front of the Louvre consists of how many panes?", "answer": "666", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133888a", "question": "What is the name of the winged horse of Greek mythology?", "answer": "Pegasus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a22c", "question": "Who played the title role in the 1981 film \"Mad Max 2\"?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b2a4e662d71a53650fdb", "question": "What are the first names of Lord Voldemort's parents?", "answer": "Tom and Merope", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59f9b733364247bf200fb86f", "question": "Who wrote \"The Scarlatti Inheritance\"?", "answer": "Robert Ludlum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339544", "question": "Who starred as Sydney Fox on the TV show \"Relic Hunter\"?", "answer": "Tia Carrere", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd3eb7e83c707845b2157", "question": "Red had how many parole hearings through out the course of the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Three", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a1a4e212f2a7826b9b8733", "question": "Which Panamanian boxer's nickname, translated into English, means \"Hands of Stone\"?", "answer": "Roberto Duran", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9094801dd7bf43be5e88d", "question": "The orbit of the planet Mercury was important in proving which scientific theory?", "answer": "General relativity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4e4", "question": "What 4 seas are named for colors?", "answer": "Red, White, Yellow and Black", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a23f", "question": "What year did Elton John release his fourth studio album \"Madman Across the Water\"?", "answer": "1971", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c04c", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Belarus?", "answer": "White stork", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2d9", "question": "How many sides does a nonagon have?", "answer": "Nine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af71", "question": "During what decade was the first US transcontinental railway completed?", "answer": "1860s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b5", "question": "What year was actor Stephen Fry born?", "answer": "1957", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4c5", "question": "What Irish city's name is Gaelic for \"black pool\"?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c96c", "question": "What is an onychophagist?", "answer": "A nail biter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b028", "question": "The major battle of what city was fought on January 8, 1815?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b41d", "question": "Johann Schober was the first president of what modern-day organization in 1923?", "answer": "Interpol", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa3913c73aa70ea0b70ad7", "question": "Which settlers added an \"r\" to Arkansas?", "answer": "French (They were told by natives from an Illinois tribe that people in the area now called Arkansas were called \"Akansa\".)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391d9", "question": "What was the official name of the first Indiana Jones movies?", "answer": "Raiders of the Lost Ark", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339890", "question": "Which of the Marx brothers had a mustache and smoked cigars?", "answer": "Groucho Marx", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4ee", "question": "What two pieces are moved in chess's castling maneuver?", "answer": "The king and rook", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f14101dd7bf43be5e803", "question": "What does the Latin root word for \"trivia\" refer to?", "answer": "Crossroads or forked road", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339173", "question": "Who played Luke Skywalker in the original Star Wars movies?", "answer": "Mark Hamill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7ccf3877e98cb97778a2f", "question": "What British island, accessible by road only at low tide, is also known as Holy Island?", "answer": "Lindisfarne", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d87", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"Charly\" based on?", "answer": "Flowers for Algernon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1f8", "question": "Telly Savalas played which TV detective?", "answer": "Kojak", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a52e", "question": "What Ivy League school is located in Ithaca?", "answer": "Cornell University", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe734eaeec85e375820b23f", "question": "Who served as Hitler's Deputy Fuhrer from 1933 to 1941?", "answer": "Rudolph Hess", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb8b", "question": "In what city did NBA star LeBron James play his high school basketball home games?", "answer": "Akron, Ohio", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b97d", "question": "What nuts are used to make a Satay sauce?", "answer": "Peanuts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6aa", "question": "What cave, found in central Kentucky, is the world's longest cave system?", "answer": "Mammoth Cave", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133952f", "question": "What actress was a regular on both \"Dynasty\" and \"TJ Hooker\" at the same time?", "answer": "Heather Locklear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339997", "question": "What TV sidekick was portrayed by Jay Silverheels?", "answer": "Tonto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d6c", "question": "Who played the role of TV's J. J. Starbuck?", "answer": "Dale Robertson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc1f1ec223966ae8f8870", "question": "Who\u2019s the only athlete who ever lit the cauldron for an Olympics and then won a gold medal at those same games?", "answer": "Cathy Freeman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce2", "question": "At what US city did Bugs Bunny traditionally lament taking a left \"toin\"?", "answer": "Albuquerque", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfb2", "question": "Macrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Long waits", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5aab2f1d58d116dab4aecb46", "question": "Banjul is the capital of which country?", "answer": "The Gambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9d3", "question": "In nautical terms, what does \"Stern\" mean?", "answer": "Behind", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e7", "question": "Who played the judge in the TV show \"Night Court\"?", "answer": "Harry Anderson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad38", "question": "George Washington was a member of which fraternal organization?", "answer": "The Freemasons", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef5c716ce05a3942286e20", "question": "Which actress keeps her Oscar in her bathroom so guests can hold it and make speeches in the mirror shame-free?", "answer": "Kate Winslet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be3a", "question": "How many players are there in a standard ultimate frisbee team?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec3", "question": "Who voiced Shaggy on \"Scooby Doo, Where Are You?\"?", "answer": "Casey Kasem", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f9f485baf848b908361b878", "question": "How many black keys are found on a traditional 88-key piano?", "answer": "36", "category": "general"}]